<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Pikmin</string>
    <string name="label_familia">Family</string>
    <string name="terrestre">Terrestrial</string>
    <string name="acuatico">Aquatic</string>
    <string name="aereo">Aerial</string>
    <string name="label_descripcion">Description:</string>
    <string name="label_caracteristica1">Feature 1:</string>
    <string name="label_caracteristica2">Feature 2:</string>
    <string name="label_caracteristica3">Feature 3:</string>
    <string name="imagen_del_pikmin_seleccionado">Selected Pikmin Image</string>
    <string name="imagen_del_pikmin">Pikmin Image</string>
    <string name="se_ha_seleccionado_un_pikmin">Pikmin %s has been selected</string>
    <string name="bienvenido_al_mundo_pikmin">Welcome to the Pikmin world!</string>
    <string name="acerca_de">About…</string>
    <string name="ajustes">Settings</string>
    <string name="desarrollado_por">App developed by Francisco Gutiérrez Ruiz</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="idioma">Spanish</string>
    <string name="tema">Dark theme</string>
    <string name="detalle_pikmin">Pikmin details</string>

    <!-- Pikmin names -->
    <string name="bearded_amprat">Bearded amprat</string>
    <string name="blue_pikmin">Blue pikmin</string>
    <string name="bulborb">Bulborb</string>
    <string name="empress_bulblax">Empress bulblax</string>
    <string name="glow_pikmin">Glow pikmin</string>
    <string name="ice_pikmin">Ice pikmin</string>
    <string name="joustmite">Joustmite</string>
    <string name="lumiknoll">Lumiknoll</string>
    <string name="peckish_aristocrab">Peckish aristocrab</string>
    <string name="puckering_blinnow">Puckering blinnow</string>
    <string name="puffy_blowhog">Puffy blowhog</string>
    <string name="purple_pikmin">Purple pikmin</string>
    <string name="pyroclasmic_slooch">Pyroclasmic slooch</string>
    <string name="red_pikmin">Red pikmin</string>
    <string name="rock_pikmin">Rock pikmin</string>
    <string name="skeeterskate">Skeeterskate</string>
    <string name="skitter_leaf">Skitter leaf</string>
    <string name="skutterchuck">Skutterchuck</string>
    <string name="swooping_snitchbug">Swooping snitchbug</string>
    <string name="toady_bloyster">Toady bloyster</string>
    <string name="waddlepus">Waddlepus</string>
    <string name="waterwraith">Waterwraith</string>
    <string name="white_pikmin">White pikmin</string>
    <string name="winged_pikmin">Winged pikmin</string>
    <string name="yellow_pikmin">Yellow pikmin</string>

    <!-- Pikmin family -->
    <string name="fam_bearded_amprat">Numbouse</string>
    <string name="fam_blue_pikmin">Pikmin</string>
    <string name="fam_bulborb">Grub-Dog</string>
    <string name="fam_empress_bulblax">Grub-Dog</string>
    <string name="fam_glow_pikmin">Unknown</string>
    <string name="fam_ice_pikmin">Pikmin</string>
    <string name="fam_joustmite">Burrow-nit</string>
    <string name="fam_lumiknoll">Unknown</string>
    <string name="fam_peckish_aristocrab">Onionshell</string>
    <string name="fam_puckering_blinnow">Elips</string>
    <string name="fam_puffy_blowhog">Blowhog</string>
    <string name="fam_purple_pikmin">Pikmin</string>
    <string name="fam_pyroclasmic_slooch">Slooch</string>
    <string name="fam_red_pikmin">Pikmin</string>
    <string name="fam_rock_pikmin">Pikmin</string>
    <string name="fam_skeeterskate">Spitterspatter</string>
    <string name="fam_skitter_leaf">Skitterling</string>
    <string name="fam_skutterchuck">Heavil</string>
    <string name="fam_swooping_snitchbug">Scarpanid</string>
    <string name="fam_toady_bloyster">Mollusking</string>
    <string name="fam_waddlepus">Flobbler</string>
    <string name="fam_waterwraith">Unknown</string>
    <string name="fam_white_pikmin">Pikmin</string>
    <string name="fam_winged_pikmin">Pikmin</string>
    <string name="fam_yellow_pikmin">Pikmin</string>

    <!-- Pikmin descriptions -->
    <string name="desc_bearded_amprat">Mouse-like creature capable of generating static energy by rubbing the hairs on its beard. Furthermore, they are mammals and, therefore, quite unusual on this planet. More research is necessary on these creatures, given that their mere existence could lead to the emergence of a completely new fauna taxonomy.</string>
    <string name="desc_blue_pikmin">Blue body and an indecipherable facial expression. Unlike most radiambulary species, which cannot breathe underwater, Blue Pikmin possess gills that are mistaken for a mouth. These gills allow them to survive in both aquatic and terrestrial ecosystems.</string>
    <string name="desc_bulborb">It has a scarlet abdomen dotted with white spots. Their habits are nocturnal, so they are usually found sleeping during the day. If awakened, they will attempt to devour anything in front of them. There is a great variety of grub-dogs, and they are considered to be at the top of the food chain.</string>
    <string name="desc_empress_bulblax">When certain environmental conditions are met, such as a sudden decrease in the species that serve as their food, the largest female grub-dog in the area assumes the role of matriarch of the group. As a result, the female grub-dog\'s egg sac swells to enormous proportions. In this state, the new Empress Bulblaxes produce a large number of larvae.</string>
    <string name="desc_glow_pikmin">Radiant green body. When the leaf on their head blooms, it takes a star shape. They have several characteristics that distinguish them from other types of Pikmin; one of them is that instead of sprouting from Onions, they sprout from Lumiknolls that are only found at night and in underground regions.</string>
    <string name="desc_ice_pikmin">They belong to a parasitic subtype of Pikmin called Puffmin. They obtain and maintain their body through a process that uses their low-temperature core to constantly generate new ice from the humidity in the environment.</string>
    <string name="desc_joustmite">They possess a hard shell that protects their head. But, while frontal attacks do not harm them, their rear is very vulnerable. This characteristic distinguishes it from the armored spikey blowhog, the first species of the family to be discovered.</string>
    <string name="desc_lumiknoll">They act as nests and incubators for Glow Pikmin. They only appear at night in places where an Onion was located during the day. Their radiant green color attracts nocturnal creatures.</string>
    <string name="desc_peckish_aristocrab">They are amphibious crabs with asymmetrical pincers. The larger right pincer can regenerate after detaching during molting, even after having been completely lost. Curiously, not only does their body resemble an Onion, but they also smell similar to it.</string>
    <string name="desc_puckering_blinnow">Many think that the aquatic water mites are not fully developed, given that they have large eyes and lack fins. The fact is that this is the normal physiognomy in the adult species. Aquatic water mites use their long caudal fin to aggressively attack their prey when it enters the water.</string>
    <string name="desc_puffy_blowhog">They use the hydrogen they generate internally to inflate a buoyancy bladder and thus remain airborne. They expel air through vents.</string>
    <string name="desc_purple_pikmin">Robust and resistant body. They are stronger and larger than the rest of their species. They weigh 10 times more than any other Pikmin. Like White Pikmin, they can only be born from rebounding sprouts that are only found in underground regions, which is why they are considered a unique species.</string>
    <string name="desc_pyroclasmic_slooch">A species of terrestrial gastropod that protects itself with flames. Instead of having a traditional shell, they are coated in a flammable mucus. If their flame goes out, it will take them more than a day and a half to relight it.</string>
    <string name="desc_red_pikmin">Scarlet-colored body and a pointed nose. In addition to the vegetal traits typical of their species, they present animal characteristics such as a strong fighting spirit and a high degree of curiosity. They have a great capacity for adaptation, as they are not only resistant to extreme heat but also tend to inhabit a wide variety of ecosystems.</string>
    <string name="desc_rock_pikmin">A parasitic Pikmin type called Puffmin that takes a rock as its host and, similar to a seed that takes root through the cracks in a rock, the Pikmin\'s roots penetrate the stone.</string>
    <string name="desc_skeeterskate">They skate on the water. They feed on plankton that they absorb, along with the water, through their tube-shaped mouth. They are territorial and use water as a weapon against small insects that approach.</string>
    <string name="desc_skitter_leaf">A type of aquatic bulborb that protects itself from predators by blending in with a green leaf similar to that of broad-leaved trees. Although it cannot float, the Leafy Bulborb can swim easily by rotating its body in the water.</string>
    <string name="desc_skutterchuck">Flat, shiny, black body. They carry small rocks on their backs. Their antennae and the fine hairs on their legs have evolved to help them detect danger in their surroundings, even in the dark. They tend to share their habitat with the larvae of the long-legged puddle-head to ensure an ample supply of rocks.</string>
    <string name="desc_swooping_snitchbug">This species greatly developed its antennae and now uses them to fly and catch Pikmin. The surface of their bodies is composed of thin layers that interfere with light and give the visual effect of a bright green coloration.</string>
    <string name="desc_toady_bloyster">They are amphibious mollusks with large gills that resemble a flower. Their eyes do not protrude as much as those of other species in the mollusk family, which evolved increasingly further away from the shell. The Puffy Blowhogs possess both male and female reproductive organs.</string>
    <string name="desc_waddlepus">They expel bubbles through their mouth and body. They may resemble octopuses, but, in reality, they are closer to starfish in terms of their anatomy. They possess five arms that, being radially distributed on the round part of their body, form a star. They live mainly near the water, but can also survive on land.</string>
    <string name="desc_waterwraith">All existing reports on the aqueous specters describe them as transparent, viscous beings with a gelatinous body that slightly resembles the human body. They move by rolling two cylindrical rocks and using their limbs to maneuver the rocks and pursue their prey. However, since they have only been seen a few times, the aqueous specters remain a great mystery.</string>
    <string name="desc_white_pikmin">White body and red eyes. Their small bodies secrete a potent poison, which in turn makes them immune to certain poisons. White Pikmin seeds can be obtained through ivory rebounding sprouts that only grow in underground regions.</string>
    <string name="desc_winged_pikmin">Pink body and prominent blue, lens-like eyes. They move swiftly through the air with their wings, but their attacks do not cause much damage.</string>
    <string name="desc_yellow_pikmin">Yellow body and a pair of ear-like lamellae that allow them to dig quickly and reach great heights when launched. Another distinguishing feature is their body\'s capacity to conduct electricity. Furthermore, not only are they resistant to it, but they seem to enjoy it.</string>

    <!-- Pikmin characteristics -->
    <string name="char1_bearded_amprat">Electricity generators: They can store electricity in their beard by rubbing their hairs. This behavior causes static energy to accumulate, which they can then discharge.</string>
    <string name="char1_blue_pikmin">Underwater Breathing: They have gills on their head that are mistaken for a mouth. These gills allow them to breathe underwater.</string>
    <string name="char1_bulborb">Nocturnal: They sleep during the day and only wake up if they feel threatened, for example, if they sense someone entering their territory. They come out to hunt when the sun sets.</string>
    <string name="char1_empress_bulblax">Larvae Birth: They can give birth to a large number of larvae, forming a group of up to 50 members. One hypothesis states that this process is a survival strategy and that the new larvae have the task of spreading to other areas with abundant food sources. However, another hypothesis suggests that the larvae are generated as an emergency nutritional source.</string>
    <string name="char1_glow_pikmin">They live in Lumiknolls instead of Onions. They have no feet and float in the air. They are immune to many elements that affect other types of Pikmin.</string>
    <string name="char1_ice_pikmin">Freezing Properties: They freeze their prey by striking them with their frigid body. They also float on the surface of the water. When grouped together, they are capable of freezing large expanses of water.</string>
    <string name="char1_joustmite">A Well-Protected Head: Thanks to the resistant shell that protects its head, it tends to charge head-on against both predators and potential prey. Unfortunately for them, their abdomen remains largely unprotected. They usually hide in the ground during the day.</string>
    <string name="char1_lumiknoll">Glow Pikmin Nests: Glow Pikmin live inside Lumiknolls. If Lumiflux pellets are transported to it, more Glow Pikmin will sprout.</string>
    <string name="char1_peckish_aristocrab">Large Pincer: They use their large right pincer to catch their prey, defend themselves from potential predators, and produce the characteristic clicking sounds of their call during mating season.</string>
    <string name="char1_puckering_blinnow">Jumping Out of Water: They sometimes use their long caudal fin to propel themselves out of the water and catch their prey.</string>
    <string name="char1_puffy_blowhog">Flight Capability: They use the hydrogen they generate internally to inflate a buoyancy bladder and stay airborne. They maintain buoyancy by orienting their fins and expelling air through the vents on their sides.</string>
    <string name="char1_purple_pikmin">Weight: They weigh 10 times more than other Pikmin. They are so heavy that, upon hitting the ground, they create gravitational waves that can cause damage. Due to their high weight, they are slower.</string>
    <string name="char1_pyroclasmic_slooch">Coated in Flames: They use an flammable mucus that coats their body to protect them from predators. They isolate themselves from the flames coating their body by constantly secreting mucus.</string>
    <string name="char1_red_pikmin">Fire Immunity: Their epidermis and muscle fibers are composed of fireproof cellulose, which allows them to have immunity to heat and fire.</string>
    <string name="char1_rock_pikmin">Unbreakable: Since their bodies are made of rocks, they are nearly indestructible, but they can be destroyed if crushed on hard surfaces.</string>
    <string name="char1_skeeterskate">Floating on Water: Their legs are covered with hydrophobic hairs which create surface tension that allows them to float on water.</string>
    <string name="char1_skitter_leaf">Mimicry: It imitates common leaves to hide from potential predators. Its stem-like tongue allows it to suck nectar.</string>
    <string name="char1_skutterchuck">Carrying Objects: They have a concave back. This allows them to carry objects easily, such as small rocks. They have been observed to look like they are wearing small hats when carrying things on their backs.</string>
    <string name="char1_swooping_snitchbug">Trapping Instinct: They use their elongated antennae to fly and catch Pikmin.</string>
    <string name="char1_toady_bloyster">Long, Thin Tongue: They use their distinctive tongues to detect their potential prey. This tongue is divided into six different ends, allowing them to capture multiple prey at once.</string>
    <string name="char1_waddlepus">Expelling Bubbles: They inflate themselves and expel bubbles to scare away approaching predators. This behavior mainly occurs to protect the eggs during spawning season.</string>
    <string name="char1_waterwraith">Transparent Body: They possess bodies that are neither liquid nor solid, making it impossible to apply any traditional classification criteria to them.</string>
    <string name="char1_white_pikmin">Poison Immunity: They are highly resistant to poisons and are immune to poisonous gases and spores.</string>
    <string name="char1_winged_pikmin">Flight Capability: They are the only type of Pikmin that can fly.</string>
    <string name="char1_yellow_pikmin">Electricity Resistance: It has been proven that, if they are exposed to electricity while in the leaf stage, their leaves will bloom. Conversely, other types of Pikmin would be electrocuted if exposed to that element.</string>
    <string name="char2_bearded_amprat">Lactation: They possess hairs covering their entire body to maintain a stable body temperature, but their abdomen is less hairy. They usually nurse their young.</string>
    <string name="char2_blue_pikmin">Excellent Swimmers: They are capable of fighting creatures underwater.</string>
    <string name="char2_bulborb">Tips for Identification: As they age, their color darkens. The white spots on their abdomen allow them to recognize others of their species. Cases have been recorded where they accidentally feed on larvae that do not have white spots.</string>
    <string name="char2_empress_bulblax">Rolling: Their body is too large to move by walking. Therefore, they drag and roll their body back and forth across the ground to move. It is not unusual for them to accidentally roll over a Bulborb larva without realizing it, as newly hatched Bulborb larvae do not have red spots.</string>
    <string name="char2_glow_pikmin">Nocturnal and Underground Activity: They are a nocturnal species. Their activities focus on protecting the Lumiknolls from predators. During the day, they take the form of seeds and remain in a state of lethargy. At night and in underground regions, they are in their regular form.</string>
    <string name="char2_ice_pikmin">Cold Immunity: They are immune to cold temperatures and cannot be frozen. However, they are very vulnerable to fire and can melt quickly. This means that flames will damage them more quickly than other Pikmin.</string>
    <string name="char2_joustmite">Needle-Shaped Mouth: They possess mouthparts that are elongated and needle-shaped, allowing them to suck fluids from the prey they pierce.</string>
    <string name="char2_lumiknoll">Loomer: It is an early phase of the Lumiknolls. Despite its smaller size, it still attracts nocturnal creatures.</string>
    <string name="char2_peckish_aristocrab">Expelling Bubbles: When on land, they expel bubbles through special valves to discharge water they have in the rear part of their mouth. To breathe, they absorb oxygen through gills that look like cheeks.</string>
    <string name="char2_puckering_blinnow">Group Swimming: They tend to swim in groups to increase the probability of catching prey when hunting.</string>
    <string name="char2_puffy_blowhog">Air Blowing Capability: They blow air onto their prey to feed and also to ward off enemies.</string>
    <string name="char2_purple_pikmin">Great Carrying Capacity: Their muscle fibers are very dense, giving them the strength of 10 normal Pikmin. The reach of their attack is similar to that of Red Pikmin. The carrying capacity of 10 normal Pikmin is equal to that of 1 Purple Pikmin.</string>
    <string name="char2_pyroclasmic_slooch">Elongated Tongue: They use their elongated tongue to catch and entangle their prey.</string>
    <string name="char2_red_pikmin">High Offensive Capability: The pointed nasal protrusions are the cause of the outstanding strength that characterizes them.</string>
    <string name="char2_rock_pikmin">Robust: They have very robust bodies. They are capable of breaking glass surfaces!</string>
    <string name="char2_skeeterskate">Shooting Water: They suck water through a tube-shaped proboscis and spit it out at predators that enter their territory.</string>
    <string name="char2_skitter_leaf">Vestigial Wings: The leaf-shaped body parts evolved from their vestigial wings, which emit a sound similar to a bell.</string>
    <string name="char2_skutterchuck">Throwing Objects: They defend themselves from predators by throwing the objects they carry on their backs.</string>
    <string name="char2_swooping_snitchbug"></string>
    <string name="char2_toady_bloyster">Expelling Ink: They can expel ink from their body when they perceive themselves to be in danger.</string>
    <string name="char2_waddlepus">Elastic Body: They possess 12 points on their elastic torso from which they can expel bubbles.</string>
    <string name="char2_waterwraith">Cylindrical Rocks: They generally move using rocks that are predominantly basaltic but also include small amounts of other rare minerals, such as nickel and cobalt.</string>
    <string name="char2_white_pikmin">Poisonous Bodies: They are lethal to creatures that ingest them.</string>
    <string name="char2_winged_pikmin">Weak Attacks: Since they have small bodies, they do not cause much damage when attacking. However, they are very persistent and, once they start attacking, they will not stop.</string>
    <string name="char2_yellow_pikmin">Elevated Flight Capability: They possess two lamellae on the sides of their head that allow them to reach great heights when launched. The distance they travel is the same.</string>
    <string name="char3_bearded_amprat"></string>
    <string name="char3_blue_pikmin"></string>
    <string name="char3_bulborb">Prominent Eyes: They have developed prominent eyeballs that allow them to have better night vision, but, due to the large size they have reached, it is impossible for them to close them completely. The way these creatures blink is through the expansion and contraction of the iris.</string>
    <string name="char3_empress_bulblax"></string>
    <string name="char3_glow_pikmin">Unusual Behavior: They exhibit behaviors not observed in other creatures. For example, they can teleport to remote locations. They also have the ability to fuse into a group to form a sphere of intense light.</string>
    <string name="char3_ice_pikmin"></string>
    <string name="char3_joustmite"></string>
    <string name="char3_lumiknoll">Luminous Nectar: They secrete a component rich in degradation enzymes.</string>
    <string name="char3_peckish_aristocrab"></string>
    <string name="char3_puckering_blinnow">Coloration During Mating: During mating season, their sides, which are normally yellow, turn a deep pink color.</string>
    <string name="char3_puffy_blowhog"></string>
    <string name="char3_purple_pikmin">Born Underground: They are only born underground when thrown into violet rebounding sprouts. This process is similar to that of White Pikmin when thrown into ivory rebounding sprouts.</string>
    <string name="char3_pyroclasmic_slooch"></string>
    <string name="char3_red_pikmin"></string>
    <string name="char3_rock_pikmin">Non-Adhesive: Thanks to the rough surface of their bodies, they cannot stick to enemy creatures and, instead, launch themselves at them to attack with their entire body.</string>
    <string name="char3_skeeterskate"></string>
    <string name="char3_skitter_leaf"></string>
    <string name="char3_skutterchuck"></string>
    <string name="char3_swooping_snitchbug"></string>
    <string name="char3_toady_bloyster"></string>
    <string name="char3_waddlepus"></string>
    <string name="char3_waterwraith">Bipedal Characteristics: Instances have been reported where they were seen walking on two legs.</string>
    <string name="char3_white_pikmin">Speed: They are the fastest of all Pikmin. Their small bodies do not cause much damage when attacking.</string>
    <string name="char3_winged_pikmin"></string>
    <string name="char3_yellow_pikmin">Excellent Diggers: They dig faster than other types of Pikmin.</string>


</resources>
